Let's look bit closer into Cross-Entropy by switching to a different example.
我们再来看看另一个示例 仔细了解下交叉熵
Let's say we have three doors,
假设有三道门
and no this is not the Monty Hall problem.
注意 这不是蒙提霍尔问题
We have the green door, the red door, and the blue door.
有绿色的门 红色的门和蓝色的门
And behind each door, we could have a gift or not have a gift,
每个门后面都可能有一个礼物
and the probabilities of there being a gift behind each door is 0.8 for the first one,
每个门后面有礼物的概率分别是：
0.7 for the second one,
第一道门为 0.8 第二道门为 0.7
and 0.1 for the third one.
第三道门为 0.1
So, for example, behind the green door there's an 80 percent probability of there
例如 绿色门后面有礼物的概率是 80%
being a gift and a 20 percent probability of there not being a gift.
没有礼物的概率是 20%
So, we can put the information in
我们可以将这些信息放入表格中
this table where the probabilities of there being a gift are
有礼物的概率
given in the top row and
放在上面一行
the probabilities of there not being a gift are given in the bottom row.
没有礼物的概率放在下面一行
So, let's say we want to make a bet on the outcome.
假设我们相对结果进行猜测
So, we want to try to figure out what is the most likely scenario here.
我们想知道最可能的情形是什么
And for that, we'll assume they're independent events.
假设它们是独立事件
In this case, the most likely scenario is just
这里 最可能的情形
obtained by picking the largest probability in each column.
是通过选择每列最大的概率来获得
So, for the first door is more likely to have a gift than not have a gift.
对于第一个门 更有可能有礼物
So, we'll say there's a gift behind the first door.
所以我们说第一道门后面有礼物
For the second door, it's also more likely that there's a gift.
对于第二道门 也更有可能有礼物
So, we'll say there's a gift behind the second door.
所以我们说第二道门后面有礼物
And for the third door, it's much more likely that there's no gift.
对于第三道门 更有可能没礼物
So, we'll say there's no gift behind the third door.
所以说第三道门后面没有礼物
And as the events are independent,
因为这些事件是独立的
the probability for this whole arrangement is the product of
整个分布的概率是
the three probabilities which is 0.8 x 0.7 x 0.9,
三个概率的积 即 0.8 x 0.7 x 0.9
which ends up being 0.504 which is roughly 50 percent.
结果为 0.504 大概是 50%
So, let's look on the possible scenarios in the table.
我们看看表格里的可能情形
Here's a table with all the possible scenarios for each door
这是表示每道门所有可能情形的表格
and there are eight scenarios since each door gives us two possibilities each.
共有八种情形 因为每道门有两种可能性
And there are three doors.
有三道门
So, we do this before to obtain the probability of
和之前一样获得每种分布的概率
each arrangement by multiplying the three independent probabilities to get these numbers.
即将三个独立概率相乘 获得这些数字
You can check that these numbers add to one.
可以发现 这些数字相加等于 1
And from the last video, we learn that the negative of
从上一个视频中 我们了解到
the logarithm of the probability is the cross-entropy.
概率对数的负值是交叉熵
So, let's go ahead and calculate the cross-entropy.
我们计算下交叉熵
Here we get these numbers.
结果是这些数字
And notice that the events with high probability have
注意 概率高的事件交叉熵低 而概率低的事件交叉熵高
high cross-entropy and the events with low probability have a low cross-entropy.
概率低的事件交叉熵也低
For example, the second row which has probability of
例如 第二行的概率是 0.504
0.504 gives a small cross-entropy of 0.69.
交叉熵是 0.69
And the second to last row which is very very unlikely has a probability
倒数第二行的概率极低 为 0.006
of 0.006 gives a cross-entropy of 5.12.
交叉熵是 5.12
So, let's actually calculate a formula for the cross-entropy.
我们来推理下交叉熵公式
Here we have our three doors and our sample scenario said that there's
这是三道门 示例情形说第一道门和第二道门
a gift behind the first and second doors and no gift behind the third door.
后面有一个礼物 第三道门后面没有礼物
Recall that the probabilities of these events happening
这些事件发生的概率是
are 0.8 for a gift behind the first door,
第一道门后面有礼物的概率是 0.8
0.7 for a gift behind the second door,
第二道门后面有礼物的概率是 0.7
and 0.9 for a no gift behind the third door.
第三道门后面没有礼物的概率是 0.9
So, when we calculate the cross-entropy,
我们在计算交叉熵时
we get the negative of the logarithm of
算出积对数的负值
the product which is the sum of the negatives of the logarithms of the factors,
也就是因子对数的负值之和
which is -ln(0.8) - ln(0.7) - ln(0.9).
为 -ln(0.8) - ln(0.7) - ln(0.9)
And in order to derive the formula without some variables.
为了推出带有变量的公式
So, let's call p1 the probability that there's a gift behind the first door,
我们称 p1 为第一道门后面有礼物的概率
p2 the probability there's a gift behind the second door,
p2 为第二道门后面有礼物的概率
and p2 the probability there's a gift behind the third door.
p2 为第三道门后面有礼物的概率
So, this 0.8 here is p1,
这里 0.8 是 p1
this 0.7 here is p2,
0.7 是 p2
and this 0.9 here is 1-p3,
0.9 是 1-p3
since the probability of there not being
因为没有礼物的概率是
a gift is one minus the probability of there being a gift.
1 减去有礼物的概率
And let's have another variable called y_i which will be one,
再设定一个变量 叫做 yi
if there is a present behind the ith door and zero, there's no present.
如果第 i 道门后面有礼物 则是 1 如果没有礼物 则是 0
So, y_i is technically a number of presents behind the ith door?
实际上 yi 就是表示第 i 道门后面有礼物的数字
In this case, y1=1, y2=1, and y3=0.
这里 y1=1 y2=1 y3=0
So, we can put all this together and derive a formula for the cross-entropy.
可以综合所有这一切得出交叉熵公式
And it's this sum.
是这个和
Now, let's look at the formula inside the summation.
我们看看和里面的这个公式
Noted that if there's a present behind ith door then y_i=1.
注意 如果第 i 道门后面有礼物 则 yi=1
So, the first term is logarithm of p_i and the second term is zero.
所以第一项是 ln(pi) 第二项是 0
Likewise, if there is no present behind the ith door,
类似地 如果第 i 道门后面没有礼物
then y_i is zero.
那么 yi 是 0
So, this first term is zero and this term is precisely logarithm of one minus p_i.
所以第一项是 0 这一项是 ln(1-pi)
Therefore, this formula really encompasses the sums of the negatives of
因此 这个公式完全包含了对数负值的和
the logarithms which is precisely the cross-entropy.
正好是交叉熵
So, the cross-entropy really tells us when two vectors are similar or different.
交叉熵可以告诉我们两个向量是相似还是不同
For example, if you calculate the cross-entropy of the pair (1,1,0)
例如 如果计算 (1,1,0)
and (0.8,0.7,0.1) we get 0.69.
和 (0.8,0.7,0.1) 的交叉熵 结果是 0.69
And that is low because 1,1,0 is a similar vector to 0.8, 0.7,
结果比较小 因为 1,1,0 是和 0.8, 0.7,0.1 相似的向量
0.1 which means that the arrangement of gifts given by the first set
意味着根据第二组数字给出的概率
of numbers is likely to happen
第一组数字得出的礼物分布
based on the probabilities given by the second set of numbers.
有可能发生
But on the other hand, if we calculate the cross-entropy of the pairs (0,0,1) and (0.8,
但是另一方面 如果计算 (0,0,1) 和
0.7, 0.1) that is 5.12 which is very high.
(0.8, 0.7, 0.1) 的交叉熵 结果是 5.12 很高
This is because the arrangement of gifts being given by the first set of numbers is
这是因为根据第二组数字给出的概率
very unlikely to happen from the probabilities given by the second set of numbers.
第一组数字表示的礼物分布不太可能发生